<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Stanford Basic Income Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Stanford Basic Income Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Unconditional Cash Impact Health Outcomes?</title>
      <link>/events/can-unconditional-cash-impact-health-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/can-unconditional-cash-impact-health-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Join us for an evening with Evelyn Forget and Marni Brownell in conversation with Marcella Alsan to discuss the impact unconditional cash transfers have on health outcomes. Forget will present her research on the influence of the Canadian Mincome experiment on health and wellbeing and Brownell will share the effects of the Healthy Baby Program&amp;rsquo;s prenatal benefit on maternal and child health outcomes.
Evelyn L. Forget is an economics Professor in the Department of Community Health Sciences at the University of Manitoba and Academic Director of the Manitoba Research Data Centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing 2019-20 Postdoctoral Research Fellow</title>
      <link>/news/lab-updates/introducing-2019-20-postdoctoral-research-fellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/lab-updates/introducing-2019-20-postdoctoral-research-fellow/</guid>
      <description>The Basic Income Lab is excited to introduce our 2019-20 Postdoctoral Research Fellow, Dr. Rebecca Hasdell.
Hasdell is a currently a Food Policy Fellow with the Food Policy Lab (Dalhousie University) and Our Food Project (Ecology Action Centre) and an Adjunct Faculty member in the Northern Medical Program (University of British Columbia). Over the past 10 years, Rebecca has worked in program planning and strategic policy for local governments, research institutions and not-for-profit organizations in the areas of poverty reduction, food access and environmental health, including leading major social policy initiatives as a City of Toronto Urban Fellow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alan Krueger / Why is Universal Basic Income So Controversial? – Discussion Seminar</title>
      <link>/events/alan-krueger-why-universal-basic-income-so-controversial-discussion-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/alan-krueger-why-universal-basic-income-so-controversial-discussion-seminar/</guid>
      <description>The Wesson Discussion Seminar is intended to be a response to the Wesson Lecture delivered by Alan Krueger on Wednesday, March 13.
Discussion Seminar Commentators
JAMES FERGUSON is the Susan S. and William H. Hindle Professor in the School of Humanities and Sciences, and Professor in the Department of Anthropology. His research has focused on southern Africa and has engaged a broad range of theoretical and ethnographic issues. These include the politics of “development,” rural-urban migration, changing topographies of property and wealth, constructions of space and place, urban culture in mining towns, experiences of modernity, the spatialization of states, the place of “Africa” in a real and imagined world, and the theory and politics of ethnography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alan Krueger / Why is Universal Basic Income So Controversial? - Lecture</title>
      <link>/events/alan-krueger-why-universal-basic-income-so-controversial-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/alan-krueger-why-universal-basic-income-so-controversial-lecture/</guid>
      <description>This lecture will discuss a form of unconditional cash transfers often called &amp;ldquo;universal basic income&amp;rdquo; (UBI). UBI can be thought of as a form of &amp;ldquo;negative income tax,&amp;rdquo; often with a zero tax rate. Evidence on the incentive effects of UBI in many contexts will be presented. The idea of a negative income tax was supported by a wide range of economists because of its efficiency properties — including James Tobin and Milton Friedman — which makes it surprising that UBI has been so controversial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Income Illusions: Lucas Stanczyk and Debra Satz</title>
      <link>/events/basic-income-illusions-lucas-stanczyk-and-debra-satz-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/basic-income-illusions-lucas-stanczyk-and-debra-satz-0/</guid>
      <description>Should basic-income strategies be prioritized over labor organization? Are unconditional cash payments to individuals the proper response to collective problems at the societal level? Join us as our panelists discuss universal basic income as a response to poverty, unemployment and inequality.
Lucas Stanczyk is Assistant Professor of Philosophy at Harvard and works on topics at the intersection of political philosophy and political economy. Prior to Harvard, he was an assistant professor of political science and affiliated faculty member of MIT&amp;rsquo;s philosophy department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give People Money: How a Universal Basic Income Would End Poverty, Revolutionize Work, and Remake the World</title>
      <link>/events/give-people-money-how-universal-basic-income-would-end-poverty-revolutionize-work-and-remake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/give-people-money-how-universal-basic-income-would-end-poverty-revolutionize-work-and-remake/</guid>
      <description>Join us for a conversation with Annie Lowrey, an economics writer and author of &amp;ldquo;Give People Money: How a Universal Basic Income Would End Poverty, Revolutionize Work, and Remake the World.&amp;rdquo; The book examines the concept of a universal basic income (UBI) and why a stipend given to every citizen might be necessary in an age of rising inequality, persistent poverty and dazzling technology.
The book also explores the potential of such a sweeping policy and the challenges the movement faces, among them contradictory aims, uncomfortable costs, and, most powerfully, the entrenched belief that no one should get something for nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Spring at the Basic Income Lab</title>
      <link>/news/lab-updates/first-spring-basic-income-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/lab-updates/first-spring-basic-income-lab/</guid>
      <description>Greetings All, Stanford University has created a new Basic Income Lab, under the director Professor Juliana Bidadanure. It is housed within the Center for Ethics in Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from the CASH Conference</title>
      <link>/news/lab-updates/highlights-cash-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/lab-updates/highlights-cash-conference/</guid>
      <description>Watch and read highlights from the Economic Security Project&amp;rsquo;s innaugural CASH Conference in San Francisco on October 19, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dorian T. Warren and Mia Birdsong / Basic Income and Racial Justice</title>
      <link>/events/dorian-t-warren-basic-income-and-racial-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/dorian-t-warren-basic-income-and-racial-justice/</guid>
      <description>Dorian T. Warren and Mia Birdsong will be explaining how universal basic income can help create a more racially just society. Warren’s presentation will discuss MLK’s and the Black Panther Party’s perspectives on guaranteed income, as well as touching upon how the Movement for Black Lives connects UBI with reparations. Following Warren’s presentation, Birdsong will talk about her Listen First Tour, which highlights the voices of those experiencing economic and racial injustice and the impact UBI would have on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Can Universal Basic Income Do For Gender Equality?</title>
      <link>/events/what-can-universal-basic-income-do-gender-equality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/what-can-universal-basic-income-do-gender-equality/</guid>
      <description>Free and open to the public. Parking for Cubberley: along Lagunita Drive behind Tresidder Union &amp;amp; in the Wilbur Field Garage. Except for the Oval, all Visitor, &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo; spots on campus are available after 4pm.
Some skeptics of a Universal Basic Income (UBI) object to the policy proposal’s component of unconditionality on the grounds of potential exploitation of net payers by net beneficiaries of a UBI. This talk argues that gender inequalities of power and resources, which are largely (but not solely), the result of women’s disproportionate responsibility for care work, must be explicitly highlighted in the argument for the unconditional component of a UBI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cities and Universal Basic Income</title>
      <link>/events/cities-and-universal-basic-income/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/cities-and-universal-basic-income/</guid>
      <description>Cities and Universal Basic Income is hosted by the Stanford Basic Income Lab, in partnership with the National League of Cities, the Economic Security Project, and the McCoy Family Center for Ethics in Society.
This event will bring together city leaders, international experimenters, researchers, and funders to substantially advance the discussion on the suitability of basic income in addressing poverty and exclusion in American cities.
We aim to:
 Share the current state of city, state/province and country-level basic income experiments around the world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Income: A Radical Proposal for a Free Society and a Sane Economy</title>
      <link>/events/basic-income-radical-proposal-free-society-and-sane-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/basic-income-radical-proposal-free-society-and-sane-economy/</guid>
      <description>Philippe Van Parijs will present on his new book, co-written with Yannick Vanderborght, in which the authors offer the most comprehensive defense of basic income, advocating it as our most realistic hope for addressing economic insecurity and social exclusion in the twenty-first century.
Philippe Van Parijs is a professor at the University of Louvain (Hoover Chair of Economic and Social Ethics), a special guest professor at the University of Leuven and an associate member of Nuffield College, Oxford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments in Unconditional Basic Income</title>
      <link>/events/experiments-unconditional-basic-income/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/experiments-unconditional-basic-income/</guid>
      <description>Experiments in Unconditional Basic Income &amp;ndash; What do people do when they&amp;rsquo;re given cash, no strings attached?
Panelists:
 Joe Huston - Regional Director, Give Directly Elizabeth Rhodes - Research Director for the Basic Income Project, Y Combinator Research Guy Standing - Professorial Research Associate at the School of Oriental and African Studies, University of London; Founder and Co-President, Basic Income Earth Network  In 2016, the policy proposal for Universal Basic Income grew more favorable in American opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Fellowships</title>
      <link>/fellowships/graduate-fellowships/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fellowships/graduate-fellowships/</guid>
      <description>Overview:
The Stanford Basic Income Lab is seeking to recruit graduate students to assist with an extensive review and mapping of research on Universal Basic Income (UBI). The ideal candidate will be trained in Politics, Sociology, Public Policy, or Economics (and related fields) and have a strong interest in learning more about UBI. To be considered, please send your CV and a short cover letter to Sarah Berger Gonzalez, Program Manager of the Stanford Basic Income Lab, at basicincomelab@stanford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</title>
      <link>/fellowships/postdoctoral-fellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fellowships/postdoctoral-fellow/</guid>
      <description>For the 2020-2021 academic year, the Lab will not be recruiting a postdoctoral fellow.
For the 2019-2020 academic year, the Stanford Basic Income Lab appointed a postdoctoral research fellow who is responsible for carrying out extensive research on basic income experiments, studying ongoing pilot designs and reviewing the findings of cash-based programs throughout the world. This research will culminate in a comprehensive report - ‘Universal Basic Income: Learning from the Global Evidence Base’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Fellowships</title>
      <link>/fellowships/undergrad-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fellowships/undergrad-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>Apply for Undergraduate Student Positions:
The Basic Income Lab is currently in the process of putting together opportunities for Stanford undergraduate students. If you are interested in getting involved in the Lab, please email basicincomelab@stanford.edu with your CV and a brief letter with information about why you are interested in basic income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Jobs and the Question of Basic Income</title>
      <link>/events/future-of-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/future-of-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Experiments in Unconditional Basic Income &amp;ndash; What do people do when they&amp;rsquo;re given cash, no strings attached?
Panelists:
 Joe Huston - Regional Director, Give Directly Elizabeth Rhodes - Research Director for the Basic Income Project, Y Combinator Research Guy Standing - Professorial Research Associate at the School of Oriental and African Studies, University of London; Founder and Co-President, Basic Income Earth Network  In 2016, the policy proposal for Universal Basic Income grew more favorable in American opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/uploads/basic-income-illusions-lucas-stanczyk-and-debra-satz-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/uploads/basic-income-illusions-lucas-stanczyk-and-debra-satz-0/</guid>
      <description>--  Basic Income Illusions: Lucas Stanczyk and Debra Satz | Stanford Basic Income Lab               Skip to content  Skip to navigation    Stanford Basic Income Lab     SUNetID Login SUNetID Login           About What is BIL? What is Basic Income?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>