<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Stanford Basic Income Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Stanford Basic Income Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for Undergraduate Student Positions</title>
      <link>/positions/undergrad-opportunities/sections/apply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/undergrad-opportunities/sections/apply/</guid>
      <description>The Basic Income Lab is currently in the process of putting together opportunities for Stanford undergraduate students. If you are interested in getting involved in the Lab, please email basicincomelab@stanford.edu with your CV and a brief letter with information about why you are interested in basic income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for a Graduate Fellowship</title>
      <link>/positions/graduate-fellowships/sections/apply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/graduate-fellowships/sections/apply/</guid>
      <description>To be considered, please send your CV and a short cover letter to Sarah Berger Gonzalez, Program Manager of the Stanford Basic Income Lab, at basicincomelab@stanford.edu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for the Postdoctoral Research Fellow Position</title>
      <link>/positions/postdoctoral-research-fellow/sections/apply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/postdoctoral-research-fellow/sections/apply/</guid>
      <description>The appointment term is for one year, from September 1, 2019 to August 31, 2020. Applicants must have completed all requirements for their Ph.D. by June 30, 2019. Candidates must also be no more than three years from the awarding of their degree (i.e., September 2016).
Applicants should submit a cover letter, CV, a writing sample (no more than 25 pages double-spaced), and three letters of recommendation no later than March 8, 2019 at 11:59pm EST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Description</title>
      <link>/positions/postdoctoral-research-fellow/sections/section3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/postdoctoral-research-fellow/sections/section3/</guid>
      <description>The Lab is interested in candidates who have research interests and experience in universal basic income or related cash transfer programs, poverty eradication, or social and economic inequality. Applicants must hold a PhD in economics, political science, public policy, psychology, sociology, or related fields. We have a strong preference for candidates trained in the social sciences with a background in empirical research methods.
As part of the Lab, the postdoctoral fellow will produce a comprehensive report, ‘Universal Basic Income: Learning from the Global Evidence Base’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Students for Empirical Research</title>
      <link>/positions/graduate-fellowships/sections/section1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/graduate-fellowships/sections/section1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Description</title>
      <link>/positions/graduate-fellowships/sections/section3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/graduate-fellowships/sections/section3/</guid>
      <description>BIL is seeking to hire up to two graduate students to review the empirical literature on Universal Basic Income under the supervision of Faculty Director Juliana Bidadanure and with the support of the Program Manager, Sarah Berger Gonzalez. The job entails extensive readings on both the theory and data of basic income. The student will be responsible for email exchanges with leading basic income researchers and experimenters throughout the world to ensure the research platform is comprehensive and accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/positions/graduate-fellowships/sections/section2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/graduate-fellowships/sections/section2/</guid>
      <description>The Stanford Basic Income Lab is seeking to recruit up to two graduate students to assist with an extensive review and mapping of research on Universal Basic Income (UBI). The ideal candidate will be trained in Politics, Sociology, Public Policy, or Economics (and related fields) and have a strong interest in learning more about UBI. To be considered, please send your CV and a short cover letter to Sarah Berger Gonzalez, Program Manager of the Stanford Basic Income Lab, at basicincomelab@stanford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/positions/postdoctoral-research-fellow/sections/section2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/postdoctoral-research-fellow/sections/section2/</guid>
      <description>For the 2019-2020 academic year, the Stanford Basic Income Lab is seeking to appoint a postdoctoral research fellow who will be responsible for carrying out extensive research on basic income experiments, studying ongoing pilot designs and reviewing the findings of cash-based programs throughout the world. This research will culminate in a comprehensive report - ‘Universal Basic Income: Learning from the Global Evidence Base’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Research Fellow</title>
      <link>/positions/postdoctoral-research-fellow/sections/section1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/postdoctoral-research-fellow/sections/section1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Opportunities</title>
      <link>/positions/undergrad-opportunities/sections/section1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/positions/undergrad-opportunities/sections/section1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>